A Guide to the William Allen Butler Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7160-a
William Allen Butler Collection 1858-1894
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7160-a
10 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1964 May 22
Item Listing
- Letters
  - D. Appleton & Co., New York, to Dear [Sirs ?], 1858 Jul 21; ALS, 2 p.
    [Includes advertising circular; considers credit risks of [Lee and Carl ?] who have "paid promptly" and [ W. B. Kern?] whom "it is not prudent to trust."]
  - William Allen Butler to J[oseph] H. Richards, 1860 Jun 25; ALS, 1 p.
    [Intends to lend an article on Palermo, written for the
    Independent
    , to Richards for his weekly paper.]
  - William Allen Butler, New York, to Howard M[alcolm] Ticknor, Boston, 1868 Apr 2; ALS, 1 p.
    [Says he sent pieces appropriate for
    [Our] Young Folks
    to Ticknor at Mr. Fields' suggestion; requests their return, as he has received no response after a month.]
  - William Allen Butler, New York, to George E. Jardine, 1878 Dec 26; ALS, 1 p.
    [Writes that poem in question was written between 1868 and 1871 and published in
    Harper's Monthly Magazine
    as well as in Butler's volume of poems.]
  - William Allen Butler, New York, to [F.] K. Howell, Newark, New Jersey, 1879 Jun 11; ALS, 1 p.
    [Responds to request for address of John Lyons by suggesting the inquiry should go to another William Allen Butler who perhaps handled the land transaction.]
  - William Allen Butler, [ New York], to John M. [Bush ?] [Burt ?], 1889 Aug 8; ALS, 1 p.
    [Responds to request for his autograph and autograph of Evert A. Duyckinck by sending his own and referring the correspondent to others for Duyckinck's.]
  - William Allen Butler, Yonkers, New York, to Cephas Brainerd, 1894 Jul 18; ALS, 3 p.
    [Thanks him for volume of New World containing account of the "MacKenzie case," suggests it was written by Daniel E. Sickels; sends brief, prepared by his father and [Charles] O'Connor, and a copy of the log of the ["Somers"] which records proceedings resulting in the mutineers execution.]
  - William Allen Butler, Yonkers, New York, to Henry Paret, 1894 Oct 27; ALS, 1 p.
    [Sends requested photograph, refers to engraved "likeness" of himself in the American Portrait Gallery. ]
  - William Allen Butler, [ New York City], Cephas Brainerd, 1894 Oct 31; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for volume of the
    New World
    containing and article on the "Somers" case; mentions another magazine piece on the topic.]